Merrill Gillespie Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Merrill Gillespie Papers.
1953-2002 (bulk 1953-1956).
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Gillespie, Merrill..
.25 linear feet.
The collection primarily consists of correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie. The bulk of the correspondence dates from 1953 to 1956 when Michael Rumaker was a student at Black Mountain College.
MSS20040029
Biography
Merrill Gillespie is a San Francisco, California.
Scope and Content
The bulk of the collection consists of letters from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie.
Related Material
Letters from Merrill Gillespie to Michael Rumaker are located in the Michael Rumaker Papers, 1957-2002. Archives & Special Collections also maintains collections of other Black Mountain artists. For detailed information on this and other related collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Gillespie, Merrill.; Rumaker, Michael.
Organizations:
Black Mountain College.
Subjects:
Black Mountain College.
Document Types:
Correspondence.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated by Mr. Gillespie in 2004.
Detailed Description
- Papers, 1953-2002
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, February - April 1953. (Box 1:1)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, May - August 1953. (Box 1:2)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, September - December 1953. (Box 1:3)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, May - September 1954. (Box 1:4)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, October - December 1954. (Box 1:5)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, February - May 1955. (Box 1:6)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, June 1955. (Box 1:7)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, July - August 1955. (Box 1:8)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, November - December 1955. (Box 1:9)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, January 5, 1956. (Box 1:10)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, 1974, 1977. (Box 1:11)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, 1980-1981. (Box 1:12)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, 1982. (Box 1:13)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, 1983. (Box 1:14)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, 1991-1992. (Box 1:15)
  - Correspondence from Michael Rumaker to Merrill Gillespie, 1996, 2002. (Box 1:16)
  - Letter from George Butterick to Merrill Gillespie, October 14, 1980. (Box 1:17)
  - Articles and ephemera regarding Michael Rumaker, n.d., 1962, 1994. (Box 1:18)